SEC. -X- _ O
2. -X- _ O
CLASS -X- _ O
SCHEDULING -X- _ O
OF -X- _ O
FENTANYL-RELATED -X- _ O
SUBSTANCES. -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
202 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
c -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
812 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
c -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
e -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Unless -X- _ O
specifically -X- _ O
exempted -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
unless -X- _ O
listed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
material -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
compound -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
mixture -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
preparation -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
contains -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
quantity -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
contains -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
salts -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
isomers -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
salts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
isomers -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
whenever -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
existence -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
salts -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
isomers -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
salts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
isomers -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
possible -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
specific -X- _ O
chemical -X- _ O
designation. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
For -X- _ O
purposes -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
except -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
means -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
structurally -X- _ O
related -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fentanyl -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
modifications -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
By -X- _ O
replacement -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
phenyl -X- _ O
portion -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
phenethyl -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
monocycle -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
whether -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
substituted -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
monocycle. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
By -X- _ O
substitution -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
phenethyl -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
alkyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
alkenyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
alkoxyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
hydroxyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
halo -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
haloalkyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
amino -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
nitro -X- _ O
groups. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
C -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
By -X- _ O
substitution -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
piperidine -X- _ O
ring -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
alkyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
alkenyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
alkoxyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
ester -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
ether -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
hydroxyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
halo -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
haloalkyl -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
amino -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
nitro -X- _ O
groups. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
D -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
By -X- _ O
replacement -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
aniline -X- _ O
ring -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
aromatic -X- _ O
monocycle -X- _ O
whether -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
substituted -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
aromatic -X- _ O
monocycle. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
E -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
By -X- _ O
replacement -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
N-propionyl -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
acyl -X- _ O
group. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
satisfies -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
definition -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
nonetheless -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
treated -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
subject -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
action -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
201 -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
otherwise -X- _ O
expressly -X- _ O
listed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
schedule. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
4 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
may -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
order -X- _ O
publish -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ B-Abstraction
Register -X- _ I-Abstraction
a -X- _ O
list -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
satisfy -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
definition -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
absence -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
list -X- _ O
published -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
does -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
negate -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
status -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
satisfies -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
definition -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`fentanyl-related -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
SEC. -X- _ O
3. -X- _ O
REGISTRATION -X- _ O
REQUIREMENTS -X- _ O
RELATED -X- _ O
TO -X- _ O
RESEARCH. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Alternative -X- _ O
Registration -X- _ O
Process -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ O
Research. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
303 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
823 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
m -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Special -X- _ O
Provisions -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Practitioners -X- _ O
Conducting -X- _ O
Certain -X- _ O
Research -X- _ O
With -X- _ O
Schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
Controlled -X- _ O
Substances. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
general. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Notwithstanding -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
substances -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
accordance -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
subsection. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Research -X- _ O
subject -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
expedited -X- _ O
procedures. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Research -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
respect -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
drug -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
subject -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
investigational -X- _ O
use -X- _ O
exemption -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
505 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
i -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Federal -X- _ I-Document
Food -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
Drug -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
and -X- _ I-Document
Cosmetic -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
conducted -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Department -X- _ B-Organization
of -X- _ I-Organization
Health -X- _ I-Organization
and -X- _ I-Organization
Human -X- _ I-Organization
Services -X- _ I-Organization
or -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Department -X- _ B-Organization
of -X- _ I-Organization
Veterans -X- _ I-Organization
Affairs -X- _ I-Organization
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
funded -X- _ O
partly -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
entirely -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
grant -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
contract -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
cooperative -X- _ O
agreement -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
transaction -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Department -X- _ B-Organization
of -X- _ I-Organization
Health -X- _ I-Organization
and -X- _ I-Organization
Human -X- _ I-Organization
Services -X- _ I-Organization
or -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Department -X- _ B-Organization
of -X- _ I-Organization
Veterans -X- _ I-Organization
Affairs. -X- _ I-Organization
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Expedited -X- _ O
procedures. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Researcher -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
current -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
i -X- _ I-Abstraction
or -X- _ I-Abstraction
ii -X- _ I-Abstraction
research -X- _ O
registration. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
general. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
or -X- _ I-Abstraction
II -X- _ I-Abstraction
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
date -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
30 -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
date -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
sends -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notice -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
containing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
respect -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
chemical -X- _ O
name -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
II -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
quantity -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
III -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Demonstration -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
category -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
demonstration -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
satisfied -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
aa -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
case -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
grant -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
contract -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
cooperative -X- _ O
agreement -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
transaction -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
intramural -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
project -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
identifying -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
sponsoring -X- _ O
agency -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
supplying -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
number -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
grant -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
contract -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
cooperative -X- _ O
agreement -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
transaction -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
project -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
bb -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
case -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
505 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
i -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Federal -X- _ I-Document
Food -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
Drug -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
and -X- _ I-Document
Cosmetic -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
supplying -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
number -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
sponsor -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
record -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
application. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
IV -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Demonstration -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
authorized -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
respect -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
laws -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
State -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
place. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Verification -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
hhs -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
va. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Upon -X- _ O
request -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
Health -X- _ I-Person
and -X- _ I-Person
Human -X- _ I-Person
Services -X- _ I-Person
or -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
Veterans -X- _ I-Person
Affairs -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
appropriate -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
verify -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
submitted -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
applicant -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
clause -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
III -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Researcher -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
current -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
i -X- _ I-Abstraction
or -X- _ I-Abstraction
ii -X- _ I-Abstraction
research -X- _ O
registration. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
general. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
or -X- _ I-Abstraction
II -X- _ I-Abstraction
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
send -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notice -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
containing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
listed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
respect -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
general -X- _ I-Person
action. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
shall -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
treat -X- _ O
notice -X- _ O
received -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
clause -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
sufficient -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
II -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
later -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
45 -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
receiving -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notice -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
contains -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
required -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
aa -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
register -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
applicant -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
bb -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
serve -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
order -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
cause -X- _ O
upon -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
applicant -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
accordance -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
304 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
c -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
4 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Electronic -X- _ O
submissions. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
shall -X- _ O
provide -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
means -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
permit -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
submit -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
electronically. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
5 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Limitation -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
amounts. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
conducting -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
substance -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
possess -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
amounts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
substance -X- _ O
identified -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
supplemental -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
send -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
needs -X- _ O
additional -X- _ O
amounts -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
supplemental -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
include -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
name -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
additional -X- _ O
quantity -X- _ O
needed -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
iii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
attestation -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
conducted -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
consistent -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
scope -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
subject -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
6 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Importation -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
exportation -X- _ O
requirements -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
affected. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Nothing -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
alters -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
requirements -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
title -X- _ O
III -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
regarding -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
importation -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
exportation -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substances. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
b -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Separate -X- _ O
Registrations -X- _ O
Not -X- _ O
Required -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Additional -X- _ O
Researcher -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Same -X- _ O
Institution. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
302 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
c -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
822 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
c -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
4 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
An -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
institution -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
conducting -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
acting -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
scope -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
professional -X- _ O
practice -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
institution -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
C -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
informs -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
name -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
position -X- _ O
title -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
employing -X- _ O
institution -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
separately -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
authorizes -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
perform -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
iii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
affirms -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
act -X- _ O
taken -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
involving -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
attributable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
directly -X- _ O
committed -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
act -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
purposes -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
proceeding -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
304 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
suspend -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
revoke -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
D -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
does -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
30 -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
receiving -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
authorization -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
affirmation -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
C -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
refuse -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
reason -X- _ O
listed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
304 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
allow -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
agent -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
employee -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
possess -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
separate -X- _ O
registration. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
c -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Single -X- _ O
Registration -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Related -X- _ O
Research -X- _ O
Sites. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
302 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
e -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
822 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
e -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Notwithstanding -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
303 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
single -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
occurs -X- _ O
exclusively -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
sites -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
city -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
county -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
II -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
institution -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
organization -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
agency -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
commencing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
notifies -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
site -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
conducted -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
II -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
stored -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
administered. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
site -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
included -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
researcher -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
notified -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
site -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
conducted -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
stored -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
administered -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
site. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
C -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
may -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
consultation -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
issue -X- _ O
regulations -X- _ O
addressing -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
respect -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
sites -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
manner -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
delivered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
sites -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
storage -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
security -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
sites -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
iii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
maintenance -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
records -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
sites -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
iv -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
matters -X- _ O
necessary -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
ensure -X- _ O
effective -X- _ O
controls -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
diversion -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
sites. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
d -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
New -X- _ O
Inspection -X- _ O
Not -X- _ O
Required -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Certain -X- _ O
Situations. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
302 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
f -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
822 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
f -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
striking -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
inserting -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
applies -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
modification -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
second -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
higher -X- _ O
numerical -X- _ O
designation -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
inspection -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
location -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
required. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Nothing -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
prohibit -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
from -X- _ O
conducting -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
inspection -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
determines -X- _ O
necessary -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
ensure -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
registrant -X- _ O
maintains -X- _ O
effective -X- _ O
controls -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
diversion. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
e -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Continuation -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Research -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Substances -X- _ O
Newly -X- _ O
Added -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I. -X- _ I-Abstraction
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
302 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
822 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
h -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Continuation -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Research -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Substances -X- _ O
Newly -X- _ O
Added -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I. -X- _ I-Abstraction
-- -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
conducting -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
added -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ I-Abstraction
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ B-Abstraction
I -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
later -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
90 -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
scheduling -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
newly -X- _ O
scheduled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
submit -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
completed -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
modification -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
existing -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
accordance -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
regulations -X- _ O
issued -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
for -X- _ O
purposes -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
notwithstanding -X- _ O
subsections -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
b -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
continue -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
until -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
withdraws -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
serves -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
order -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
cause -X- _ O
proposing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
denial -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
304 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
c -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
serves -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
order -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
cause -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
requests -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
hearing -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
hearing -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
held -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
expedited -X- _ O
basis -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
later -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
45 -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
request -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
except -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
hearing -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
held -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
later -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
requested -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
4 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
sends -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
copy -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
manufacturer -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
distributor -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
receipt -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
copy -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
manufacturer -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
distributor -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
constitute -X- _ O
sufficient -X- _ O
evidence -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
authorized -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
receive -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Treatment -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Certain -X- _ O
Manufacturing -X- _ O
Activities -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
Coincident -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Research. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
302 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
822 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
e -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Treatment -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Certain -X- _ O
Manufacturing -X- _ O
Activities -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
Coincident -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Research. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
general. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Except -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
registered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
perform -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
perform -X- _ O
manufacturing -X- _ O
activities -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
quantities -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
activities -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
required -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
obtain -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
manufacturing -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
activities -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
performed -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
purpose -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
activities -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
quantities -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
involved -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
activities -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
stated -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
submitted -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
303 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
l -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
protocol -X- _ O
filed -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
approval -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
303 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
iii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
that -X- _ O
includes -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
name -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registrant -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
II -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
attestation -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
conducted -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
quantities -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
manufactured -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
consistent -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
scope -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
basis -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
registration. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Activities -X- _ O
included. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Activities -X- _ O
permitted -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
include -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
processing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
create -X- _ O
extracts -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
tinctures -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
oils -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
solutions -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
derivatives -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
forms -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
consistent -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
i -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
notification -X- _ O
submitted -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
303 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
l -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
ii -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
protocol -X- _ O
filed -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
registration -X- _ O
approval -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
303 -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
f -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
dosage -X- _ O
form -X- _ O
development -X- _ O
studies -X- _ O
performed -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
purpose -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
requesting -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
investigational -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
drug -X- _ O
exemption -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
505 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
i -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Federal -X- _ I-Document
Food -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
Drug -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
and -X- _ I-Document
Cosmetic -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
355 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
i -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
. -X- _ I-Document
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Exception -X- _ O
regarding -X- _ O
marihuana. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
authority -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
manufacture -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
does -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
include -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
authority -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
grow -X- _ O
marihuana. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
g -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Transparency -X- _ O
Regarding -X- _ O
Special -X- _ O
Procedures. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Section -X- _ B-Document
303 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Controlled -X- _ I-Document
Substances -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
21 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
823 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
amended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
n -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Transparency -X- _ O
Regarding -X- _ O
Special -X- _ O
Procedures. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
general. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
determines -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
respect -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
substance -X- _ O
should -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
considered -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
process -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
subject -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
criteria -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
different -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
process -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
criteria -X- _ O
applicable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
applications -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
schedule -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
shall -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
posting -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
website -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Drug -X- _ B-Organization
Enforcement -X- _ I-Organization
Administration -X- _ I-Organization
-- -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
identities -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
determinations -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
process -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
criteria -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
applied -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
applications -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
C -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
process -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
criteria -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
differ -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
process -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
criteria -X- _ O
applicable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
applications -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
conduct -X- _ O
research -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
controlled -X- _ O
substances -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
schedule. -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Timing -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
posting. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
shall -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
upon -X- _ O
making -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
determination -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
regardless -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
whether -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
practitioner -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
submitted -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
application -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
time. -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
SEC. -X- _ O
4. -X- _ O
RULEMAKING. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Interim -X- _ O
Final -X- _ O
Rules. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
-- -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
later -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
date -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
enactment -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
Act -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
issue -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
implement -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
Act -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
amendments -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
Act -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
issue -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
interim -X- _ O
final -X- _ O
rules. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
b -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Procedure -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Final -X- _ O
Rule. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Effectiveness -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
interim -X- _ O
final -X- _ O
rules. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
rule -X- _ O
issued -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
as -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
interim -X- _ O
final -X- _ O
rule -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
become -X- _ O
immediately -X- _ O
effective -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
interim -X- _ O
final -X- _ O
rule -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
requiring -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
to -X- _ O
demonstrate -X- _ O
good -X- _ O
cause -X- _ O
therefor -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
notwithstanding -X- _ O
subparagraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
553 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
b -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
title -X- _ I-Document
5 -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
United -X- _ I-Document
States -X- _ I-Document
Code. -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Opportunity -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
comment -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
hearing. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
An -X- _ O
interim -X- _ O
final -X- _ O
rule -X- _ O
issued -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
give -X- _ O
interested -X- _ O
persons -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
opportunity -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
comment -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
request -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
hearing. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Final -X- _ O
rule. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
After -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
conclusion -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
proceedings -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Attorney -X- _ B-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
shall -X- _ O
issue -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
final -X- _ O
rule -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
implement -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
Act -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
amendments -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
Act -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
accordance -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
553 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
title -X- _ I-Document
5 -X- _ I-Document
, -X- _ I-Document
United -X- _ I-Document
States -X- _ I-Document
Code -X- _ I-Document
. -X- _ O
SEC. -X- _ O
2. -X- _ O
NO -X- _ O
NET -X- _ O
INCREASE -X- _ O
IN -X- _ O
CERTAIN -X- _ O
FEDERAL -X- _ O
LANDS. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
General. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
For -X- _ O
acquisition -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
the -X- _ I-Person
Interior -X- _ I-Person
or -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
Agriculture -X- _ I-Person
that -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
result -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
net -X- _ O
increase -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
total -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
acreage -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
jurisdiction -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
National -X- _ B-Organization
Park -X- _ I-Organization
Service -X- _ I-Organization
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
United -X- _ B-Organization
States -X- _ I-Organization
Fish -X- _ I-Organization
and -X- _ I-Organization
Wildlife -X- _ I-Organization
Service -X- _ I-Organization
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Bureau -X- _ B-Organization
of -X- _ I-Organization
Land -X- _ I-Organization
Management -X- _ I-Organization
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Forest -X- _ B-Organization
Service -X- _ I-Organization
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
concerned -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
offer -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
sale -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
equal -X- _ O
number -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
acres -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
jurisdictional -X- _ O
status. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
b -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Exemptions. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
apply -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
easements -X- _ O
acquired -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
the -X- _ I-Person
Interior -X- _ I-Person
to -X- _ O
facilitate -X- _ O
management -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ O
lands -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ B-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
Agriculture -X- _ I-Person
to -X- _ O
facilitate -X- _ O
management -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ O
lands. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
c -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Consideration. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
general. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Land -X- _ O
sold -X- _ O
pursuant -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
subsection -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
offered -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
sale -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
fair -X- _ O
market -X- _ O
value -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
based -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
local -X- _ O
comparable -X- _ O
sales -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
price -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
reduced -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
10 -X- _ O
percent -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
month -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
sold -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
contract -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
sold -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
date -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
6 -X- _ O
months -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
offered -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
sale. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Exception. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
Time -X- _ O
periods -X- _ O
during -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
contract -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
sale -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
withdrawn -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
market -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
counted -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
purposes -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
price -X- _ O
reduction -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
paragraph -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
B -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
d -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Existing -X- _ O
Rights. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
sale -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ O
lands -X- _ O
pursuant -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
subject -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
valid -X- _ O
existing -X- _ O
rights. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
e -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Proceeds -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Sale -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Lands. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
All -X- _ O
net -X- _ O
proceeds -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
sale -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ O
lands -X- _ O
pursuant -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
shall -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
deposited -X- _ O
directly -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Treasury -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
reduction -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
debt -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
SEC. -X- _ O
2. -X- _ O
PROHIBITION -X- _ O
ON -X- _ O
FEDERAL -X- _ O
FUNDS -X- _ O
FOR -X- _ O
CERTAIN -X- _ O
LABOR -X- _ O
ORGANIZATIONS. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
General. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
No -X- _ O
Federal -X- _ O
funds -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
labor -X- _ O
organization -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
members -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
education -X- _ O
professionals. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
b -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Definitions. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
1 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Education -X- _ O
professional. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
education -X- _ O
professional -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
means -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
individual -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
employed -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
elementary -X- _ O
school -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
secondary -X- _ O
school -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
local -X- _ O
educational -X- _ O
agency -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
State -X- _ O
educational -X- _ O
agency -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
institution -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
higher -X- _ O
education. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
2 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
ESEA -X- _ O
terms. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
terms -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
elementary -X- _ O
school -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
local -X- _ O
educational -X- _ O
agency -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
secondary -X- _ O
school -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
State -X- _ O
educational -X- _ O
agency -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
meanings -X- _ O
given -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
terms -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
8101 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Elementary -X- _ I-Document
and -X- _ I-Document
Secondary -X- _ I-Document
Education -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
1965 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
20 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
7801 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
3 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Institution -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
higher -X- _ O
education. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
institution -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
higher -X- _ O
education -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
meaning -X- _ O
given -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
101 -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
Higher -X- _ I-Document
Education -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
20 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
1001 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
4 -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
Labor -X- _ O
organization. -X- _ O
-- -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
`` -X- _ O
labor -X- _ O
organization -X- _ O
'' -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
meaning -X- _ O
given -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
section -X- _ B-Document
2 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
5 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
of -X- _ I-Document
the -X- _ I-Document
National -X- _ I-Document
Labor -X- _ I-Document
Relations -X- _ I-Document
Act -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ O
29 -X- _ B-Document
U.S.C. -X- _ I-Document
152 -X- _ I-Document
( -X- _ I-Document
5 -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
) -X- _ I-Document
. -X- _ I-Document
